Hello everyone and welcome
back to the English pod.
My name is Marco and my name is Catherine
and it's the holiday season That's right.
It's almost Christmas
and so we are bringing you
one of the most typical Christmas
songs with Christmas carols
I guess the in all over the
world probably that's right,
and I've heard it in many
different languages even Chinese
Okay, I'll have to ask
yeah, yeah, yeah to ask
but yeah, we're talking
about jingle bells today
So the famous song jingle
bells you'll hear it everywhere
Especially during the Christmas
season. I only during the Christmas
season and so let's listen to
the song the song is pretty long
It has like a couple of different Versus
but we've taken the main one the first one
and the chorus, which are
like the most famous ones
So let's listen to the song
Through the snow in a one horse
or from sleigh or the fizz we come
Laughing all the way
Making squirrels right what fun is to
ride and sing the sleighs all the night
jingle bells jingle bells jingle on the way
Oh, what fun is to ride
one or something straight
jingle bells jingle bells jingle
Bell's jingle Bell's jingle on the way
Oh This is gonna be stuck in my head all
day Marco. I know it's kind of catchy though
How can you not get into the
spirit with this song? Well as you said
a Carol a Christmas Carol is a
song and they're meant to be catchy
You know you get them
in your head and they stay
there forever I think
it's also because every
Mall or shopping center you go to
they're playing the song so they're
just kind of get stuck in your
head in the background all the time
Yeah, exactly makes you want
to shop more or kill someone
All right, so there were
probably a couple of
different words that you
didn't understand here
So we're gonna go through the whole song
a little by little and we'll explain it
So starting out with the first line.
It says dashing through the snow
Well, okay, this is
interesting because in
sports there's an event
called a 100 meter dash
Mm-hmm. Okay, so a dash is
a very quick run very fast, right?
That's right, so dashing
through the snow as you're
kind of running or going
through the snow very quickly
But we don't know who is
running through the snow
But we know something
or someone is going very
quickly through the snow
and then the second line
It says in a one
horse open sleigh.
Okay, so now we know who's
dashing through the snow
It's a horse it's a horse in a and you're
in a sleigh. Okay, so an open sleigh
It means that there's no roof
So you're sitting under
the stars and there's a
horse pulling your
sleigh through the snow.
Okay So a sleigh is kind of
like a vehicle for the snow, right?
There's no wheels okay
because it's it's hard to drive
in snow and so this is an
old kind of vehicle that has
Maybe wood or metal underneath to
make it slide to make it slide very good
All right, and then we
have this strange word here
It's oh apostrophe ER or or the
field we go or that fields we go
Well, this is very very
common in poetry.
Okay, so this is a way
to make the word over
Shorter because over you
can hear it two syllables over
But sometimes we only want one so
we say or okay or the fields we can over
Okay, interesting laughing all the way
Bells on bobtails ring now. What are
bobtails? What are these bells on bobtails?
Okay, well bobtails are
the tails of certain animals.
Okay, so we could say we have
a bunny rabbit with a bobtail
That means the tail sticks
up, but it's also maybe
reindeer have bobtails
because their tails stick up
You can see them. Okay, so I guess
in this case because it's Christmas
These animals like reindeer and
rabbits have little bells on them
That and according to the
next line making spirits bright
Right, so you're making
people happy. That's right.
Spirit is your your attitude
or your soul and then this case
You're making you're
being made happy.
You're happy because it's Christmas.
You're outside very good and
Well, he says what fun it is to laugh and
sing a slaying song tonight now slaying
We know that sleigh is this vehicle to
go through this. No, but a slaying song
I guess is is the song we
sing when we're in a sleigh
So this isn't a real word, but this
is something that makes the song
kind of makes you think that these
people are just singing a special song
For being in a sleigh. All
right, and now we go to the
chorus jingle bells jingle
bells. So this word jingle
It's a verb, right? Yeah, to jingle
We can do it with your keys to to jingle is
to make noise when metal is touching metal
So we have bells and they
think think think think think
think think they get each
other. I got some keys here
I'll show you what
jingling is so we go like this.
Oh, it's a jingle
your keys, right?
Yeah Exactly, so you can use it
with keys with bells can use it with
anything else anything that makes
the sound like that times jingle
Okay, chimes jingle. All right, very good
So jingle all the way or what fun it is
to ride again in a one horse open sleigh
So all the way. Maybe
we're going someplace all
the way wherever you're
going home or to dinner and
What fun it is to ride in
a one horse open sleigh?
So the chorus is not very
hard and either is the first first,
but you know sometimes
the song the song is pretty fast
So sometimes you don't really
understand what they're saying personally
I did not know the lyrics of jingle
bells until we started doing this
Well because when we sing it we mumble,
you know, you can't hear all the words
You don't know the words, but
dashing through the snow and
sometimes you have to think
of it very clearly very good
So that's all the words
we have for this podcast.
It's it's a very good
Christmas Carol
It's very catchy and is I don't know how
old it is. I've heard it since I was small
Well probably old enough to come
from a time when there weren't cars
because there is sleigh and when
they use ore because I don't see
People use ore anymore now. I
think it's mostly just songs and poems.
You see it a lot in the
19th century, right?
And but it is interesting also, I
guess the the relationship between
Like the slaves and snow and
why don't Christmas is always
related to this even though,
you know in some places
You don't have snow during Christmas.
That's right
But it does I mean we're here in Shanghai
and and we can hear people singing a song
So and there's no snow
so I think it's just a it's
a way to think about the
season of Christmas and
The attitude of people
when it's Christmas time.
Right. So I hope you
enjoyed our lesson
If you have any questions
about this Christmas
Carol, you can let us know
on English pod dot com
And we'll also post the other
verses the less known versus of
Jingle bells because it's
actually a pretty long song
very long and I don't
know any of the other verses
Exactly so we chose the first one and the
chorus because it's the most popular one
So we'll see you guys there and
Merry Christmas Merry Christmas
You